# Jonah Tabb

Indianapolis, IN • 317-409-1247

jonahtabb@gmail.com

Junior Full-stack Developer Linked In: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonahtabb">https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonahtabb</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jonahtabb">https://github.com/jonahtabb</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://jonahtabb.github.io/portfolio">https://jonahtabb.github.io/portfolio</a>

## **Objectives**

Determined and creative **Junior Full-Stack Web Developer** looking forward to solving problems and collaborating with experienced developers to quickly increase the value I can add to the team and the product. Work well on a team with a focus on communication and sharing knowledge. Looking forward to a challenging career in web development, and continuing to grow my proficiency with Javascript and React.

## Competencies & Functional Skills

Full-stack Software & Web Design | Technical Project Management | Customer Service | Creation & Delivery Issues Troubleshooting | Agile Methodology | Continuous Process Improvement | Server-Side Development | Time

Management | Effective Communication

Databases: SQL Server, PgAdmin, Postgres SQL, Relational database management

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, APIs, stateless components, session validation, responsive web design

CI/CD: Agile, Scrum, Git, GitHub

Languages: JavaScript, Node.JS, React, Heroku & Firebase deployment, TypeScript

Other Technologies: Figma, Webflow, Zapier, Zenkit, Streak, Zoho Creator, Trello, Notion, Canva, Miro

## Education

### Web Development Immersive Learning Program - In-progress

Eleven Fifty Academy, Indianapolis, IN

12-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding full-stack web apps.

### Associate in Applied Science in Horticulture Production - 2015

College of Lake County

# Technical Projects

## Designed 'Weather Watch App' for users to add weather widgets on dashboard in-browser

- Captured data and images from multiple API endpoints using HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap 4, and Figma.
- GitHub at <a href="https://github.com/jonahtabb/api\_challenge\_2">https://github.com/jonahtabb/api\_challenge\_2</a>
- Deployed using Firebase at <a href="https://weatherwatch-abbf7.web.app/">https://weatherwatch-abbf7.web.app/</a>

Built 'Community Compost App' for neighbors to organize and coordinate a door-to-door compost pickup service

- Solo developed this full-stack single page, responsive app utilizing Typescript, React, React-Router, Class-Components, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML.
- Backend built with over 20 CRUD routes using Express, Node.js, postgeSQL, and sequelize.
- Front-end code on Github at https://github.com/jonahtabb/community\_compost\_client
- Back-end code on Github at https://github.com/jonahtabb/community\_compost\_server
- Deployed using Heroku at <a href="https://jtabb-community-compost.herokuapp.com">https://jtabb-community-compost.herokuapp.com</a>

## Developed a 'Yum App' for cooks, searching recipes by ingredients and adding them to online cookbook database.

- For this group project we build the front and back-end using React.js and Material UI. My contributions include
  pagination, external REST API calls, dynamic data display, and responsive design. Tech stack includes Express.js,
  Sequelize, Node.js, and PostgresQL. Features also include token-based authorization, and password encryption.
- Front-end code on GitHub at <a href="https://github.com/jonahtabb/yum-client">https://github.com/jonahtabb/yum-client</a>
- Back-end code on GitHub at https://github.com/jonahtabb/yum-server
- Deployed using Heroku at <a href="https://jtabb-yum-app.herokuapp.com/">https://jtabb-yum-app.herokuapp.com/</a>

# **Professional Experience**

Gather Sky Virtual Event Production, Self Employed,, Indianapolis IN

Jan 2020 - Present

### Virtual Event Producer and Platform Developer

- Designed and developed a custom virtual on-demand documentary viewing platform for over 500 events from conception through till go-live phase using Webflow, Zapier, Zenkit, and JavaScript.
- Provided continuous improvement and adjustments to the platform in order to meet the customer requirements.
- Delivered live production support to users and customers for over 150 virtual events.
- Designed 50+ process automations for optimizing business efficiency using Zapier, JavaScript, Streak CRM, and other productivity integrations.

Mad Farmers Collective, Indianapolis IN

Mar 2020 - Present

#### **Vegetable Grower**

- Grew over 70 varieties of produce using a variety of data points and environmental factors. Advised senior members with the selection and purchase of seed, fertilizer, and equipment.
- Collaborated with a team to implement the plan for the growing season.
- Leveraged creative and flexible problem solving capabilities to address unexpected challenges.

Teter Organic Farm, Noblesville IN

Jan 2016 - Mar 2020

#### Farm Manager

- Managed production details and created business plans for over 100 sub-species of crops.
- Organized forecasts, prepared schedules, identified market demands, analyzed data, managed crop timelines, estimated yields, and maintained a proper record of crops.
- Assembled budget estimates for the higher management in order to allocate resources appropriately and meet company goals.
- Coordinated and communicated with groups of 10 150 volunteers for work days and public speaking events.
- Arranged weekly pickups of vegetables for over 65 families.

## Additional Experience